PUJAN SHRESTHA

pujan.shrestha@ttu.edu | 1(208)240-5956 1002 Frankford Ave, Lubbock, TX, 79416, US

Website: www.pujanshrestha.com

INTRODUCTION

Prospective Data Analyst with a demonstrated ability to deliver valuable insights via data analytics and advanced data-driven methods. Experienced at creating data regression models, using predictive data modeling, and analyzing data mining algorithms to deliver insights and solutions to complex business problems

EDUCATION

Texas Tech University, Rawls College of Business: GPA 3.40/4.0 Bachelor of Business Administration, Information Technology **Richland College, Dallas County Community College:** GPA 3.92/4.0 Associate of Science

Dallas, TexasGraduation: December 2018

Graduation: December 2020

Lubbock, Texas

<u>Relevant Coursework:</u> Analytics and Development with Python, Database Management System, Systems Design, Emerging Technology, Business Statistics, System Security, Business Computer Application, System Analysis, Business Communication, Information Systems Project Management, Production & Operation Management

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

- Programming: R, Python & MySQL
- IDE: R-Studio , Jupiter Notebook, MYSQL Workbench
- Data Visualization: Tableau, Power BI, Matplotlib, ggplot
- Web Scraping: Scrapy, URLLIB, Pandas
- Machine Learning: Classification, Reinforcement
- Data Analysis: Data Wrangling, EDA

RECENT PROJECTS (www.pujanshrestha.com)

- R Programming: Soccer trends Analysis
- MySQL: Website Databases & Password Management
- Python: NBA Trend Data Scraping and Visualization
- Tableau: Advanced Covid19 Interactive Dashboard

CERTIFICATION

- TABLEAU: Desktop Certified Associate
- W3: Certified SQL Developer

- MICROSOFT: Certified Microsoft Office Excel Specialist
- **COMPTIA:** Certified CompTIA IT Fundamentals

EXPERIENCE

Texas Tech University, Hospitality

Lubbock, Texas

Student Assistant, Stangel Hall:

September 2018 – December 2020

- Managed and coordinated hundreds of clients in an organized manner to prevent any delay and obstacles to timely and seamless service delivery
- Performed training and workshop for trainees (20+) leading to better team formation for the year 2019/2020

LEADERSHIP

Rawls Student Council

May 2019 – May 2020

- Gather feedback from students and work closely with Dean on issue's student has in the Rawls College of Business, TTU
- Encourage communication between students, faculty and the administration and contribute to projects and data recording using Excel, MySQL, and Tableau

Leo Club Kathmandu, Nepal

October 2015 - August 2016

 Presented and implemented New Database and Order System (Focused more on Simplicity and User Friendly) for Clubs Membership track

HONOR & AWARDS

Texas Tech University: Scholarship and Financial Aid

July 2019/August 2020

- Earned Jesse Mickey Memorial Endowed Scholarship: Demonstrated ability to work on the frontier of Information Tech
- Received Proven Achiever Transfer Scholarship: Result of excellent Academic Score (3.92/4.0) in Associate of Science

Phi Theta Kappa/ Texas Region/ Alpha Alpha Xi Chapter

February 2018

• Achieved 3.5+ GPA during Sophomore & Junior year, gaining admittance to scholastic honor society

Leo Club Kathmandu, Nepal: General Member and IT guidance

January 2016

Awarded 100% Attendance & Responsible Personal Award, 2015-2016